# Darshan Washimkar

😭 3649 Garnet Street #220, Torrance, CA 90503

🖢 970-232-0660 💌 darshan.wash@gmail.com

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/darshanwashimkar

http://darshanwashimkar.github.io

#### PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I am a **Software engineer** holding a **master's degree** in computer science. With **3 years** of diverse **industry experience** in software development, **object oriented programming, algorithms and data structure**, I am looking for a software developer/engineer opportunity.

## **TECHNICAL EXPERTISE**

C, C++, JAVA, Python, JavaScript, HTML, C#

Node.js, jQuery , HTML5, JSON, PHP

MySQL, Oracle, MongoDB, SQL

Git, Mercurial

Amazon Web Services (AWS), Hadoop

> TCP,IPv4/6, BGP, Chord

> Agile- Scrum, Waterfall

> Eclipse, GDB, JIRA, Virtualbox

Programming languages

Web development

Databases

**Versioning Tools** 

Cloud services/tools

**Networking Protocols** 

Methodologies

Other Tools

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

• Software Engineer

Nov 2016 – Present

Los Angeles, CA

Nevelex Corporation

- Solved high priority defects in DirecTV set-top box software which directly impacts customers
- o Handled crucial JAVA and C++ applications named druid, MOCA manager and webkit
- Worked with JIRA, eclipse, GDB, remote debugger, mercurial, ubuntu to track and resolve defects
- Wrote unit tests using junit, mockito and gtest frameworks for bug patches

## Graduate Teaching Assistant

Jan 2015 – Dec 2015

Colorado State University

Fort Collins, CO

- o Assisted professors with classes such as "computer security", "computer networks and the internet", "advanced computer networking" and "foundations in programming"
- o Conducted two recitations every week for a batch of 30 students

Developer

Jan 2014 – Jan 2015

Colorado State University

Fort Collins, CO

- Delivered a translator module for BGP Monitoring System which converts Multi-Threaded Routing Toolkit (MRT) files to XML format using C and C++
- o Developed visualization tools using KML to simulate DDoS attack events like NTP reflection attack
- o Designed, developed and managed website for the BGPmon project

# Programmer Analyst

June 2011 - Sept 2013

Cognizant Technology Solution

Pune, INDIA

- o Programmed websites and mobile applications using JavaScript, jQuery, CSS, HTML 5, Node.js, boostrap, JAVA, ASP.net for world's top pharmaceutical and financial firms
- Employed agile- scrum methodology to develop various projects

#### **EDUCATION**

# Master of Science, Computer Science

Colorado State University, Fort Collins, CO, USA

GPA: 3.86/4.00

• Master thesis: "Error Correcting Optical Mapping Data": Developed the first non-proprietary method for correcting errors from DNA sequence bar code (known as Optical mapping data). Redundant information present in the data is used to rectify 83% of the errors.

# Bachelor of Technology, Information Technology

May 2011

Shri Guru Gobind Singhji Institute of Engineering and Technology, Nanded, MH, India

GPA: 7.8/10

### **AWARDS & CERTIFICATIONS**

- o Innovative gaming application award for the web app "Honey Bee"
- o "Low Cost Solutions Project Of The Year" for highest efficiency in developing websites and mobile apps
- o Microsoft certification in programming HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3 (Exam 70-480)

### **ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

# Optimal Selection of Enzyme Triad Using MapReduce

Oct 2014 - Dec 2014

- Proposed a new method to find best restriction enzyme triad from ~11 million combinations using
   MapReduce
- o Implemented the algorithm in **hadoop** using **python** to distribute the task of finding shared sub strings in suffix tree

# Forecast Use Of A City Bikeshare System

Nov 2014 – Dec 2014

- o Implemented linear (LLS) and non-linear models(Neural Networks) to predict the demand for bike sharing system
- o Code implementation was in **python** and the results were submitted to kaggle for competition
- o Showed that non-linear model performs much better for this problem

## Cloud based Source-aware key- value store

Oct 2014 - Dec 2014

- o Distributed Hash Table (DHT) implemented from Chord paper using Java
- Used cloud computing environments like Amazon Web Services (EC2,EBS) for development

#### Genome Assembler

Aug 2014 – Dec 2014

- o Implemented a sparse de Bruijn graph for genome assembly from scratch in C++
- Performed in depth theoretical investigations into various succinct data structures for de Bruijn graph optimization

#### A P2P File Sharing Network

Feb 2014 – Mar 2014

- o Project involved development of peer to peer file sharing network that uses protocol resembling BitTorrent
- Implementation of socket programming, fork, event loops was in C language

# A File Sharing Protocol Over Named Data Networks (NDN)

Mar 2014 – Apr 2014

- o Project was implemented using CCNx library from ccnx.org in C
- O Compared performance of the protocol in IP vs NDN configuration and found that NDN gave much better performance

## Low Cost Supercomputer with Cluster Computing

Aug 2010 - Apr 2011

- o Built a simple-to-manage and easy to deploy HPC cluster from outdated PCs of college laboratory aiming to run compute intensive software applications in an academic setting
- Used HPLinpack to evaluate the performance

Aug 2016